<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Tux Press</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Tux Press</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Sherlock Holmes 2022-2023</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 18:29:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 17:49:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>What is this? This is a blog about music, programming, math (and maybe) gaming.
Who made this? Me (Sherlock Holmes) and Tux both contribute to the content of this blog.
Where can I subscribe to this blog? We support both email and rss.
Email </description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-this&#34;&gt;What is this?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a blog about music, programming, math (and maybe) gaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-made-this&#34;&gt;Who made this?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me (Sherlock Holmes) and Tux both contribute to the content of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;where-can-i-subscribe-to-this-blog&#34;&gt;Where can I subscribe to this blog?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We support both email and rss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;email&#34;&gt;Email&lt;/h2&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dimitri Shostakovich and Why Is He Great</title>
      <link>/posts/2022/12/shostakovich/shostakovich/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 18:29:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2022/12/shostakovich/shostakovich/</guid>
      <description>My friends and I run a programming discord community. Frequently, we will deviate from the topic of programming into something else, like music. Whenever music is brought up though, 2 words will always pop up: Dimitri Shostakovich. That is because the server owner and I both enjoy his works greatly. I think now is the time to explain why we enjoy his works so much.
His Early Life Shostakovich was born in 1906 in Russia, just in time for the Russian Revolution, where we see the Bolsheviks (Russian: Большевики́) overthrow the Russian Empire.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;My friends and I run a programming discord community.  Frequently, we will deviate from the topic of programming  into something else, like music.  Whenever music is brought up though, 2 words will always pop up: Dimitri Shostakovich.  That is because the server owner and I both enjoy his works greatly.  I think now is the time to explain why we enjoy his works so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;his-early-life&#34;&gt;His Early Life&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shostakovich was born in 1906 in Russia, just in time for the Russian Revolution, where we see the Bolsheviks (Russian: Большевики́) overthrow the Russian Empire.  During that period, new morden musical techniques from the east are still tolerated in the Soviet Union, and Shostakovich was greatly influenced by them.  Listen to this example from his 2nd Symphony:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MupXrzqYZpA?start=78&amp;end=90&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, after the revolution, the authorities became less and less tolarant of western culture, and the offical art form of the Soviet Union was announced: Socialist Realism.  This limitation on artistic expression forced artists and composers to create music deemed “suitable for the party” and all content published had to be approved by the authorities.  This harsh limitation caused Shostakovich to hide double meaning in many of his famous pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear Algebra: the beginning</title>
      <link>/posts/2022/12/linalg_start/linalg_start/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2022/12/linalg_start/linalg_start/</guid>
      <description>Just gonna start working through Linear Algebra Done Wrong by Sergei Treil, probably gonna die&amp;hellip;</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Just gonna start working through Linear Algebra Done Wrong by Sergei Treil, probably gonna die&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
